# **METHA BABU**

#### **UI DEVELOPER**

methababu@outlook.com

Skype id: methababukr +91 9344428777

#### SUMMARY:

Total Year Experience: 4.6 Year

Strong Hands on development experience on Angularis and Angular 2 +

Strong knowledge on SINGLE PAGE APPLICATION design using ANGULAR JS.

Strong knowledge on JavaScript, JQuery, Angular, Typescript

Strong Hands on experience on WordPress

Strong Knowledge on HTML, CSS

Strong Knowledge on Core PHP, html, css, Codeigniter Framework.

Well experienced in using version control systems subversion (SVN), GIT.

Well experienced in using Developer tools (Eclipse IDE, NetBeans, Dreamweaver, Visual

Studio, Notepad++, Sublime)

Strong knowledge of SEO

PSD to html conversion Attractive Responsive Design

PSD to Angular conversion and then json data implementation.

PSD to react conversion.

Attractive Responsive Design with Optimized code sprite Image and svg animation.

Backend PHP codeigniter framework create Rest API.

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE:-

Project 1 March-2018 to feb-2019

Client: Cidaas

Duration: 11 Months
Project: Multicrm

Position: User Interface

Contribution:

- PSD to Angular 6 Conversion Image Slices
- Make Sprite SVG Icons
- Create Responsive Design Mobile and tablet Cross Browser

- Implement Services API data.
- Implement Angular ngchart
- Build Application and then handling gitlab Version control

## Project 2:

Client: DNC

Duration: 5 Months

Project: School Web Application

Position: User Interface

Contribution:

- PSD to Angular 6 Conversion Image Slices
- Make Sprite SVG Icons
- Create Responsive Design Mobile and tablet Cross Browser
- Implement Services API data.
- Build Application and then handling bitbucket Version control

## Project 3:

Client: Eurofins
Duration: 4 Months

Project: Company Profession Docuemtation policy

Position: User Interface

Contribution:

PSD to HTML conversion,

Create Responsive Attraction design

WOW Animation plugin implementation. Create Svg Animation

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: - 4.6 Yrs.

Client: Pichkaari design Studio, Jul 2017 - till date

Role : UI Developer

Tech Stack : HTML5 - CSS3 - WordPress - Angular - JQuery, JavaScript -- PHP

Responsibilities:

• Responsible for creating the look and feel of the public website

- Responsible for implementing functionality and responsive website.
- Creating the custom directives and making the reusable components
- Creating Angular services like Factory & Services
- Creating dynamic workflows using MXGraph lib.
- Consuming the REST APIs and showcasing the data to UI layer.
- PSD to html conversion.
- PSD to Angular Conversion and then json data implementation

Client: Nbays IT Solusenz, Jun 2014 - Jun 2016

Role : Web Developer

Tech Stack : HTML5 - CSS3 - PHP - JQuery, JavaScript, WordPress

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for creating the look and feel of the public website
- Static and dynamic Websites and then Website Optimization
- SEO Optimization.
- Create REST API PHP codignitor Framework
- Create WordPress Website theme customization.

Client: Avolot Technologies, Jun 2013 – Jun 2014

Role : Web Developer

Tech Stack : Angular - PHP- HTML5-CSS-jquery, JavaScript

Responsibilities:

- Static Website and Dynamic website
- Create own content management system
- Angularjs l x API implementation.
- Anglarjs1x create reusable code directive, factory, services and controller.

Client : Blaze Web Service Jan 2013

Role : Trainee (6- Months Intern)

Tech Stack :PHP - html5 - css Product : Hotel Management system

## Responsibilities:

- Designing & Developing HTML5 layout with Responsive Web Development standards.
- Creating Custom components and integrating with application.
- Creating & Consuming REST APIs using PHP.
- Integrating third party OAuthentication

#### **EDUCATION:**

B. Tech Information Technology, Pannai college of engineering and Technology Sivagangai

## Career Foot prints:

2013 Jan – 2013 Jun Web developer - Internship Blaze Web Services Madurai

2013 Jun – 2014 Aug Junior Web Developer Avolot Technologies Madurai

2014 Aug – 2017 Jun Web Developer Nbays It Solusenz Madurai

2017 Jun – Till date Web Developer Pichkaari Design Studio Bangalore